Guide to the Warren Jay Vinton papers, 1932-1969
Vinton, Warren Jay papers, 1932-1969
- Series XII. U.S. Congress Joint Committee on Housing, 1947-1948
  - "Joint Committee to Investigate Housing Shortage- 1947-1948"-Correspondence and memoranda to and from Sen. Robert Gamble, chairman of Joint Committee and appointment of Philip Glick and Warren Vinton to represent Public Housing Administration; reports by Gamble on progress Dec. 1947, Sen. Joe McCarthy, Vice Chairman Feb. 1948 and following speech, by W.J. Vinton on administration of low-rent housing program Dec. 1947; unrevised charts in responses to request fo Dec. 1947 on low rent question and disposal of capital assets, correspondence concerning criticism of Los Angeles Housing Authority, Sept. 22, 1939-Sept. 8, 1947 (Box 11)
  - "NPHC Releases on Subcommittee's Hearings"-[National Public Housing Conference]: Newsletters (MC) covering hearings and activitites of Joint Committee on Housing in cities across the US, highlighting roles of Sen. Joe McCarthy and Rep. Chas. Fletcher and attacks on financial administration of Public Housing Authority, Oct. 13-Dec. 4, 1947 (Box 11)
  - "Extra material re: Joint Committee on Housing Hearings (Dec. 22, 1947)"-Memorandum from Joint Committee on Houisng to Raymond Foley, Housing and Home Finance Agency Administrator requesting information memorandum from J.T. Egan, Commissioner, Public Housing Administration outlining reply, charts and financial statements used in reply, Dec. 22, 1947-Jan. 7, 1948 (Box 11)
  - "Extra material re: Joint Committee on Housing Hearings (Dec. 30, 1947)"-Memoranda and replies in answer to request for information from Joint Committee on Housing of Dec. 30, 1947 covering administrative employment and expenses, revisions and corrections of financial statments, regulations under Hatch Act of activities of personnel, summary of principal activities of Public Housing Administration, Jan. 13-27, 1948 (Box 11)
  - "Joint Committee on Housing (Requet of Dec. 22, 1947)"-Memorandum from Joint Committee on Housing to Raymond Foley, Administration, Housing and Home Finance listing questions to be prepared for Committee hearing of Jan. 12, 1948, memo on departmental reply and charts on finance and expenditures, corrections to Jan. 14, 1948 in binder file, Dec. 22, 1947-Jan. 14, 1948 (Box 11)
  - "Joint Committee on Housing (Request of Dec. 22, 1947)"-Memorandum from Joint Commitee on Housing to Raymond Foley, Administrator, Housing and Home Finance Agency, giving second installment of questions to be prepared for Commitee hearing of Jan. 12, 1948; charts and summary of principal activities in answer in binder file, Dec. 30, 1947 (Box 11)
  - "Slum Clearance Report by Senator Wagner"-Senator Wagner's report on slum clearance to Joint Committee on Housing in outline form (TS), press release of letter (MC), TS rewrite and MC questionnaire, Oct. 12, 1947-Jan. 12, 1948 (Box 11)
- Series XIII. Housing Act
  - 1949
    - "Draft of Bill-folder 1 thorough introduction of S. 138 in Senate" (Box 22)
    - "Drafts of Bill-folder 2 Up to Consideration by Subcommittee in Senate" (Box 22)
    - "Draft of Bill-folder 3 Through Introduction of S. 1070" (Box 22)
    - "Draft of Bill-folder 4" (Box 22)
    - Housing Act of 1949, 81st Congress 1st session; Bills: S. 138, Jan. 5, 1949, 5 confidential committee prints, Jan-Feb.; S. 1070, Feb.-April; HR 4009 April and union calendar 232 April; HR 236 June 1949; summaries, amendments statements by Egan (MC), urban renewal provisions of S. 1070 (duplicates) (Box 27)
    - "S. 138-S. 1070 Public Law 171"- Congressional Debate; Congressional Record Clippings, Voting Record-S. 1070; Amendments (Box 22)
    - Public Law 171, 81st Congress 1st session, S.1070, 1949- ".. .to provide Federal aid to assist slum-clearance projects and low-rent public housing.. ." (Box 11)
    - "H.R. 4009-SPENCE Companion to S. 1070- P.T. 171" Congressional Debate; Congressional Record Clippings; Bills and Reports (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, HR Committee on Banking and Currency; hearings before Committee on Banking and Currency, HR, on HR 3009, 81st Congress 1st session (2 copies), April and May 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, HR Report from the Committee on Banking and Currency to Accompany H.R. 4009; H.R. Report #590, 81st Congress, 1st session (2 copies), 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress H.R. Committee of Conference, Conference Report [to accompany S. 1070], H.R. Report #975, 81st Congress, 1st session (2 copies), July 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress Joint Committee on Banking and Currency; U.S. Housing Act as it Would be Amended by S. 138; Committee print, Feb. 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency, Supplemental Report [to accompany S. 1070], S. Report #84 pt. 2, 81st Congress, 1st session, Feb.-March 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress Joint Committee on the Economic Report. Low-Income Families and Economic Stability. Materials on problem of Low-Income Families; Joint Committee print assembled by Subcommittee on Low-Income Families of the Joint Committee on the Economic Report. Washington, D.C.: Gov. Printing Office, 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress Joint Committee on the Economic Report: Low-Income Families. Hearings before the Subcommittee on low-income families of the Joint Committee on the Economic Report on Sec. 5 (A) of Publication 304, 81st Congress, 1st session, Dec. 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, An Act (the Housing Act of 1949); publication #171, 81st Congress, Chapter 338, 1st session, S. 1070 (2 copies) (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, An Act-(the Housing Act of 1937) to improve housing conditions and to create a U.S. Housing Authority, and other purposes. Public Law #412, 75th Congress, Chapter 896, 1st session, S. 1685. (2 copies, one "CORRECTED PRINT") (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency, General Housing Legislation. Hearings before a subcommittee of committee on Banking and Currency, Senate, S. 138, 81st Congress, 1st session (2 copies), Feb. 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency; Summary of Provisions of National Housing Act of 1949. S. Document #99, 81st Congress, 1st session (2 copies), June-July, 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Report from the Committee on Banking and Currency to Accompany S. 1070. S. Report #84, 81st Congress, 1st session, 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Senate, Subcommittee of Committee of the Committee on Banking and Currency Hearings.. .on S. 138.. .bills pertaining to general housing legislation. Washington, GPO, 1949 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Housing and Finance Agency, Office of Administrator, A Handbook of Provisions of the Housing Act of 1949, Washington, D.C., July, 1949 (Box 22)
    - U.S. Housing Act as amended by Housing Act of 1949, Public Law 171, 81st Congress; "For Agency use only" annotated proposed changes as of 1/9/50 (Box 27)
  - 1950
    - S. 2246, 81st Congress, 2nd session; Public Law 475, chapter 94; House Conference report to accompany S. 2246, April; Summary of act; Bill HR 7402, Feb.; Bill S. 2246, Feb.; Senate Committee on Banking and Currency report, February, duplicates; Senate Subcommittee of Committee of Banking and Currency Hearings on Middle-Income Housing, pts 1 and 2 and supplement; Joint Committee on Economic Report Subcommittee on Low-Income Families, Materials on Problems of Low-Income Familes and Report; Cooperative Housing: hearings of House Commitee on Banking and Currency; Senate reports on domestic cooperative housing and cooperative housing in Europe; House report on cooperative housing abroad, duplicates (Box 27)
  - 1954
    - HR 7839, 83rd Congress, 2nd session; Public Law 560, chapter 649; summary of provisions of Act; House Conference report, House Minority report, House Committee on Bank and Currency for Union Calendar, Senate Committee on Banking and Currency [with] views of Mr. Lehman; Senate hearing on Housing Act, House hearing on Housing Act; U.S. Housing Act of 1937 as amended (MC) (Box 27)
  - 1955
    - Housing Amendments of 1955, Public Law 345, 84th Congress, 1st session, S. 2126 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House of Rep., Consideration of S. 2126, Report #1565 to accompany HR 326, 84th Congress, 1st session, 1955 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House of Rep., Committee on Banking and Currency; Housing amendments of 1955, hearings on HR 5827 (superseded by S. 2126); May 23.. .June 10, 1955, Washington, GPO (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House of Rep., Housing Amendments of 1955, Report #913 to accompany S. 2126, 84th Congress, 1st session (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House of Rep., Housing amendments of 1955, Report #1622 to accompany S. 2126, 81st congress, 1st session (Box 11)
    - U.S. Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency, Report 404 together with teh individual views of Mr. Bush.. .to accompany S. 2125, 84th Congress, 1st session, Washington, GPO, 1955 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Senate, Subcommittee of the Committee on Banking and Currency, Hearings on. ..bills to amend the National Housing Act, the housing Act of 1950.. .May 10-20, 1955, 84th Congress, 1st session, Washington, GPO (Box 11)
    - U.S. Federal housing Administration; Brief Summary "Housing Amendments of 1955." (Box 11)
    - U.S. President (Eisenhower)-Statement by the President, Aug. 11, 1955 (Box 11)
  - 1956
    - HR 11742, 84th Congress 2nd session, Public Law 1020, chapter 1029; House Conference report, House summary, House Committee on banking and currency report, Senate Committee on banking and currency report to accompany S. 3855, 1956 (Box 27)
    - U.S. Dept. of Interior, Housing and Home Finance Agency, Office of the Administrator; Urban renewal provisions.. .and excerpts from other federal laws authorizing federal assistance to slum clearance and urban redevelopment and urban renewal, 1956 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House of Rep., Housing Act of 1956, hearings on HR 10157, 84th Congress, 2nd session, May 7-25, 1956 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate-a bill to amend the U.S. Housing Act of 1937, as amended, to authorize assistance in the provision of housing for elderly families, S. 2762 84th Congress, 2nd session, 1956 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Subcommittee of the Committee on Banking and Currency, Housing amendments of 1956; Hearings on various bills to amend the federal housing laws, 84th Congress, 2nd session, March 20-29, 1956 (Box 11)
  - 1957
    - HR 6659 85th Congress, 1st session; Public Law 85-104; House Conference report, H and HFA summary, House Committee on Banking and Currency report; Bills April-May; House Congressional Record, June 27; section by section summary (MC), proposed revision TS bill S. 2159 (Box 27)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Committee on Banking and Currency, Subcommittee on Housing, Hearings, 85th Congress, 1st session, March 4-15, 1957 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Public Law 85-104, 85th Congress, July 12, 1957, HR 6659 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Subcommittee of the Committee on Banking and Currency, Housing amendments of 1957, Hearings, March 18-April 4, 1957, 85th Congress, 1st session (Box 11)
    - U.S. Senate, Subcommittee of the Committee on Banking and Currency; Urban renewal in selected cities, hearings, 85th Congress, 1st session, Washington, GPO, 1957 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Housing Act of 1937, as amended, July 12, 1957, so Stat. 888; 42 U.S. Code 1401, annotated (Box 21)
  - 1958
    - Correspondence, meeting notes, statements, etc., Jan-May 1958 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence from NAHO, notes on meeting with Commissioner Slusser, committee prints, extracts from Congressional Record,annotated, June-July 1958 (Box 10)
    - S. 4035, 85th Congress, 2nd session, acts, July, August, Bill (Confidential Committee print), July House Summary of committee pring, House Comittee on Banking and Currency report, bill S. 4323, Aug. 1958 (Box 27)
    - Urban Assistance and Public Housing Administration-"Tentative Drafts of Bills for the Creation of an Urban Assistance and Public Housing Administration, Related Purposes," #1-12 (MC), Feb.-May, 1958 (Box 10)
    - Items #7-10 (numbered in red) by Vinton relating to Housing Act, 1958 (Box 10)
    - Items #14-27 (numbered in black) by Vinton relating to Housing Act 1958; digest, committee prints, reports, bills, etc. (Box 10)
    - Statements and analyses by Housing and Home Finance Agency of proposed bill, annotated (Box 10)
    - Statements, press releases, correspondence, analysis of bills, etc. collected by Vinton, some annotated; includes series of NHC newsletters on Act. (Box 27)
    - Summaries, reports, extracts from housing act, 1958 (Box 10)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Committee on Banking and Currency, Subcommittee on Housing, hearings, July 7-18, 1958, 85th Congress, 2nd session (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Committee on Banking and Currency, Subcommittee on Housing, Slum Clearance and related housing problems, hearings, 85th Congress, 2nd session, Jan. 7-9, 1958 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, House: Rep. Barratt O'Hara introducing HR 12879 Housing Conservation and Rehabilitation Finance Act and HR 12878, a bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 in regard to expenditures for rehabilitation and modernization of residential structures; Congressional Record (not printed at Govt. expense), 85th Congress, 2nd session, June 10, 1958 (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Housing Challenge of America; extention of remarks of Sen. Joseph S. Clark, Aug. 18, 1958, 85th Congress, 2nd session, Congressional Record (not printed at Govt. expense) (Box 11)
    - U.S. Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency, Communitiy facilities act of 1958, hearings on S. 3497, March 19-26, 1958, 85th Congress, 2nd session (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Subcommittee of hte Committee on Banking and Currency; hearings, May 12-22, 1958, 85th Congress, 2nd session (Box 11)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency, Report #1732, together with individual and minority views to accompany S. 4035, 85th Congress, 2nd session (Box 11)
  - 1959
    - A bill to extend and amend (MC) (Box 21)
    - Comparision of Draft Ominbus Housing Bill Prepared on Behalf of Public Interest Groups and S. 57; Jan. 9, 1959 (MC, 3 copies, 2 annotated) (Box 21)
    - Comparision of Urban Renewal provisions in Senate and House versions S. 57 (MC, annotated) (Box 21)
    - Congressional Record, Senate Jan. 9-12, 1959 (Box 21)
    - S. 2539, bill as reported/passed in Senated (8 pieces) reports, copies of Congressional Record, #1-5, 1959 (Box 21)
    - S. 2654 Housing Act Bill, report, Ms notes, Congressional Record, #1-5, 1959 (Box 21)
    - S. 57, Housing Act of 1959, Sparkman Bill, reports, committee prints, Congressional Record, etc. #1-25 + duplicates (Box 21)
    - Provisions Facilitating Use of Urban Renewal Sites for Low-Rent Housing 2/2/59 (4 copies) (Box 21)
    - S. 59, "The Public Interest position on the amendments.. ." (Box 21)
    - S. 2357, Housing Act of 1959; working copy of bill, summary, committee prints etc. + duplicates #1-4 (Box 21)
    - National Housing Conference, Relocation Housing for Displaced Families or Person 1/10/59 (2 copies) (Box 21)
    - National Housing Conference; Summary of Housing Act of 1959 (MC). (Box 21)
    - National Housing Conference Summary of Housing Act of 1959; Public Law 86-372 (2 copies) (Box 21)
    - 1959 Housing Legislative Proposals S. 57 and House version.. .Comparison of differing provisions and Public Interest Group support postitions (TS, 2 copies) (Box 21)
    - Public Housing Administration-U.S. Housing Act of 1937 as amended Sept. 23, 1959 (3 copies, annotated) (Box 21)
    - Recommendations for Conference on S. 57-Re: Cooperative Housing Provisions Based on Difference Versions as Passed by Senate and House (MC, annotated) (Box 21)
    - Section by Section Analysis of Housing Act of 1959 (S. 612) proposed by Housing and Home Finance Agency 1/15/59 (MC) (Box 21)
    - Section by Section Summary of bill for the Housing Act of 1959 (2 pieces, dubplicates, MC) (Box 21)
    - Section by Section Summary of Housing Act of 1959 (MC) (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House, a bill to extend Housing Act of 1959 HR 2385, 86th Congress, 1st session, Jan. 15, 1959 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Committee on Banking and Currency S. 57 as passed by the Senate, and the House Version of S. 57 as reported by House Committee on Banking and Currency (MC) (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Committee on Banking and Currency, Housing Act of 1959 Report #86 on S. 57, 86th Congress, 1st session, (3 copies) (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House-HR 2357, January 15, 1959, 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House-HR. 2357- "before introduction" (annotated) (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House-Report #1040 [to accompany S. 2539] 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House-HR 2385, January 15, 1959, 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House-HR 3319, January 26, 1959, 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House-HR 7117, May 14, 1959, bill: Improvement of housing and renewal of urban communities etc., 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Subcommittee on Housing, hearings, 86th Congress, 1st session, January 30, 1959 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Subcommittee of the Committee on Appropriations; Independant officer appropriations for 1960, 86th Congress, 1st session part 2, incomplete volume (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, House, Subcommittee on Housing, Summary of Subcommittee Print [Committee Print]. (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, an act to extend and amend, Housing Act of 1959, Publ. L. 86-372, 86th Congress, S. 2654 (7 copies), Sept. 23, 1959 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 467, January 17, 1959 Amend title II of Housing Amendments of 1955 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 194, amending Title III of Housing Act of 1950 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 266, January 14, 1959, bill to authorize urban renewal grants, encourage state participation in slum clearnce, 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 26)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 612, January 21, 1959, bill extend, amend laws, relating provision and improvement of housing and conservation of urban communitites (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 1431, March 16, 1959; a bill to provide for the establishment of a Commission on Metropolitan Problems with clipping from Congressional Record (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 195, January 12, 1959; bill relating to foreclosure of FHA mortages (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, a bill, Housing Act of 1959, January 15, 1959 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency, hearings.. .86th Congress, 1st session, January 22, 1959 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Committee on Banking and Currency, Housing Act of 1959, Report 41, together with individual views to accompany S. 57, 86th Congress, 1st session, (2 copies) (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, Subcommittee of the Committee on Banking and Currency, President's message disapproving S. 57, hearings, 86th Congress, 1st session, July 1959 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 193, January 12, 1959, Housing Amendments of 1959, 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 21)
    - U.S. Congress, Senate, S. 2539, Housing Act of 1959, 86th Congress, 1st session (Box 21)
  - 1960
    - S. 3670, 86th Congress, 2nd session; press releases recommendations, sections of bill, extracts from Congressional Record of Senate and House, MS notes, bills HR 12603, section by section summaries, HR committee on Banking and Currency report, 1960 (Box 27)
  - 1961
    - S. 1922, 87th Congress, 1st session; public law 87-70; Committee print May; House Conference report, House print of Message from President, Senate Committee on Banking and Currency Report, Senate Committee on Banking and Currency print of section by section analysis of S. 1478, House Committee on Banking and Currency subcommittee print of section by section analysis HR 6028, House Committee on BAnking and Currency subcommittee print on possible amendments to HR 6028, Senate Committee on Banking and Currency section by section summary of S. 1922; digest of principal provisions; extracts from Congressional Record and Daily Digest, notes, analysis (MC, TS) (Box 27)
  - 1964
    - S. 3049, 88th Congress, 2nd session; Public Law 88-560, House pring of Message from President, Senate Committee on Banking and Currency report, Senate Committee on Banking and Currency section by section analysis, Senate Committee on Banking and Currency Questions, on S. 2468; analyses and summaries, largely from National Housing Conference (Box 27)
  - 1965
    - Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965, HR 7984, 89th Congress, 1st session; House Committee on Banking and Currency, Highlights of Housing and Urban Development Act; House Committee on BAnking and Currency Correction of Misleading and False Statements.. ., House Committee on Banking and Currency Compilation; Senate Committee on Banking and Currency Hearings, March and April, excerpts from hearings, House Committee on Banking and Currency hearings, part I, March, Subcommittee print of section by section summary (MC) section by section analysis (MC) (Box 27)
- Series XIV. Warren Jay Vinton Speeches and Publications, 1936-1964, arranged by year
  - "Speeches and Publications-1936"-Binder of notes, texts and transcripts of speeches (TS and A) programs of meetings, etc. (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications 1937"-Binder of notes, texts, transcripts of speeches (TS and A), programs (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications 1938"-Binder of notes, texts, transcripts of speeches (TS and A); programs (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications 1939-Binder of notes, texts, memorandum and transcripts (TS, MC and A); programs (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications 1940-1942"-Binder of notes, texts, transcripts (TS and A); programs (no speeches dated 1942) (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1943"-Binder of notes, texts, statistics, transcripts (TS, A, MC) offprint of article (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1944"-Binder of notes, texts, statistics (TS, A, MC); programs (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications,"-1945-1948, Binder of notes and texts (TS, MC, A) published article (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1949"-Binder of notes and texts (TS, MC, A) published articles (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1950"- Binder of notes and texts of speeches (MC, TS, A) programs (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1951"-Binder of notes, statistics, texts of speeches (MC, TS, A), article, programs (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications- 1952"- Binder of notes and texts (TS and A); program (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications- 1953"-Binder of notes and texts (MC, TS and A); printed articles (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1954"- Binder and loose texts of speeches (TS and MC) (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1955"- Texts of speeches (A, TS and MC); printed address "Public Housing and Financing" to Municipal Forum of New York and covering correspondence (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1956"-Texts of speeches and notes (TS), correspondence, newspaper articles (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1957"- Speeches and articles (MC, TS) (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1958"- Notes (MS) and Speeches (MC) speech at American Society of Planning Officials Conference and National Association Housing and Redevelopment Association Meeting (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications-1959"- Speech (MS) (Box 16)
  - "Speeches and Publications- 1960"- Speech (MS) (Box 16)
  - Speeches and Publications- A New Program for Housing and Community Development Resolutions Adopted by the Membership of the National Housing Conference, 1961 (Box 16)